Melanie Green

07887 935990 · Email · LinkedIn · Online CV · New Milton, Hampshire

A highly organised, versatile, and determined digital communications professional with wide-ranging experience in leading web projects, content management, development, distribution, and providing technical support. Proficiency in numerous digital platforms, products, and tools, I possess strong planning skills, tackle new challenges head on and am dedicated to delivering nothing less than quality.

Products, platforms, and tools experience

Web content management/development

- Kentico Kontent proficient at managing and editing web content.
- **DevOps** confident writing user stories for web development.
- VS Code adept at creating and editing html and css files.
- GitHub familiar with using to host examples of my work.
- SharePoint Microsoft 365 competent in managing files and editing content on the company intranet.
- Monsido experienced in monitoring and maintaining site health in quality assurance, accessibility, and SEO.

Admin and analytics

- Microsoft 365 web applications experienced in using Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Teams and Outlook.
- Google Analytics/GA4, Hotjar, Power BI, Google Tag Manager and Google Business Console familiar with using a range of tools to track, monitor and analyse performance across company websites.

Other

- Photoshop skilled in editing images/designing collateral and using Adobe Acrobat Pro to create editable pdfs.
- Social media management/Orlo oversee the management and administration of Facebook users and ad accounts, company LinkedIn pages and Twitter profile.
- QR Code Generator introduced new process for creating and managing QR codes on behalf of the business.
- Google Business Profiles implemented new process to ensure all reviews are responded to within 24 hours.
- **Poppulo** extensive knowledge of the internal communications platform from creating and sending employee emails, to providing training and technical support.
- Vimeo and Camtasia comfortable uploading, managing, and editing video content.

Work experience

Digital Channel Lead - Customer Communications - Sovereign Housing Association October 2021 to date

- Responsible for the ongoing management and development of content on company website.
- Maintain positive working relationships with internal product owners and third-party developers to identify
 ways of enhancing the cms and websites to continually improve the customer experience and enable the
 organisation to deliver effective digital communications.
- Work closely with colleagues to support the production of engaging digital content. Advise on accessibility, SEO best-practice where applicable.

IC Content Lead - Sovereign Housing Association August 2018 – October 2021

- Implemented an effective editorial process and comprehensive content planner to coordinate the communications content activity across all channels on behalf of the corporate affairs function.
- Successfully coordinated, produced, delivered and distributed weekly employee newsletters to over 2,000 employees.
- Championed the brand guidelines advised colleagues on key messaging and tone of voice.

Communications Assistant - Sovereign Housing Association February 2016 - July 2018

- Designed a range of collateral suitable for professional print and online such as posters, infographics, press coverage boards and icons.
- Event management coordinated senior management away days and networking events.
- Analytics reporting collated monthly statistics and analysed results help to make informed decisions regarding internal communications channels and content.
- Liaised with external suppliers to coordinate group print requirements and managed day-to-day relationships to ensure costs were monitored, deadlines were met, and service delivered was of a high standard.

Group Communications Assistant - FirstPort November 2013 - February 2016

• As above

HR Assistant - FirstPort November 2013 - February 2016

• Provided administrative support for the Human Resources department.

Assistant Manager - GlamorousAmorous.com February 2009 - January 2013

- Managed, processed, and dispatched all orders received.
- Updated company website daily added new product ranges, amended inventory figures, edited product information and refreshed visuals.
- New brand onboarding from initial meeting with designer and negotiating terms and conditions, to loading products/profile onto the website and product promotion.
- Managed ongoing product promotion for all brands, competitions, and latest news on social media.

Qualifications and training

- CIM Level 4 Certificate in Professional Marketing (Digital Marketing)
- WAIO.1X: Introduction to Web Accessibility
- Code First Girls Introduction to Web development, Coding and Python
- Currently working through freeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design Certification
- CIPR Specialist Certificate in Internal Communications
- RSA II Certificate in Administrative procedures